davidplusworld.com 2019-12-16

# Privacy Policy | David + World

## Disclaimer

Just like every hobbyist blogger on earth, I’m not a lawyer and it’s ridiculous that a law (with good intentions, I actually think it’s a good idea) requires us to be able to write such a legal document and put on the same level a small blog like this one and sites with billions of users and thousands of lawyers. Oh well… I just hope I won’t go to jail because I forgot a comma somewhere.

## Who we are

Our website address is: https://www.davidplusworld.com.

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: https://automattic.com/privacy/. After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact forms

This site uses a contact form. If you fill it, you’ll send information with it (your name, e-mail address, text as well as IP), they will be stored on the site and in its owner’s inbox as long as he doesn’t delete them. They will never be share with anyone else though (unless the contact form plugin collects those too, no idea).

### Cookies

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracing your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website.

### Analytics

This site uses some analytics software such as Google Analytics. A bunch of data are collected from your visit (where from, how long on the site, etc). They’re all completely anonymous and used for statistical purpose only.

## Who we share your data with

The data collected by this site will never be shared with anyone. However, some plugins used by the site may collect data too, and you need to go check the privacy policies of those plugins to see what they share with whom (yes, this is a bit ridiculous, I understand)

## How long we retain your data

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

## What rights you have over your data

If you have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes.

## Where we send your data

Visitor comments may be checked through an automated spam detection service.

## Your contact information

You can [contact us there](https://www.davidplusworld.com/contact/).
